<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steven&#39;s Snippets</title>
    <link>https://SV1124.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Steven&#39;s Snippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2024 Steven Verschoot</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://SV1124.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Final report on technical guidelines cross-border AIFM/UCITCs notifications</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/final-report-on-technical-guidelines-cross-border-aifm-notification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/final-report-on-technical-guidelines-cross-border-aifm-notification/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is a stricly personal opinion and cannot be considered legal advice.&#xA;Right before Christmas, ESMA released its final report on draft technical standards on the notifications for cross-border marketing and cross-border management of AIFS and UCITS, after processing the responses it received on its consultation in this respect that closed on 9 September 2022.&#xA;The main changes made to the original standards are the following:&#xA;a requirement to provide a LEI was introduced; the information to be provided on delegation arrangements was toned down; and the information to be provided on marketing strategy was toned down.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPACS and the AIFMD - ESMA keept it at &#39;might not be&#39;</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/spacs-and-the-aifmd-esma-keeps-it-at-might-not-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/spacs-and-the-aifmd-esma-keeps-it-at-might-not-be/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is a stricly personal opinion and cannot be considered legal advice.&#xA;On the very same day as Belgian crypto exchange Bit4You cancelled its SPAC IPO, and only shortly after the New York Times declared ‘game over’ on SPACs, ESMA has addressed whether managers of SPACS are subject to the AIFMD in an update of its AIFMD Q&amp;amp;A .&#xA;This question is relevant, as being subject to AIFMD would trigger a whole set of regulatory rules, including a license requirement, liquidity rules etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some remarks on ESMA&#39;s statement on FTX</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/some-remarks-on-esma-statement-on-ftx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/some-remarks-on-esma-statement-on-ftx/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is a personal opinion and cannot be considered legal advice.&#xA;As ESMA points out itself at multiple instances, it was not involved in the case - neither as a regulator nor as a supervisor. As such, it could be expected that ESMA’s remarks would be well-measured, calling for further regulation on governance of crypto service providers and basically a ‘so this is why we need MiCA and/or further regulation’ (which indeed turned out to be the case).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
