<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sub-Threshold AIFMs on Steven&#39;s Snippets</title>
    <link>https://SV1124.github.io/tags/sub-threshold-aifms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sub-Threshold AIFMs on Steven&#39;s Snippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2025 Steven Verschoot</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://SV1124.github.io/tags/sub-threshold-aifms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A brief FAQ on AIFMD II</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/a-brief-faq-on-aifmd-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/a-brief-faq-on-aifmd-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The final texts of AIFMD II were (finally) made available &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.consilium.europa.eu/doc/document/ST-14932-2023-INIT/en/pdf&#34;&gt;on the website of the council&lt;/a&gt; last autumn. Although not yet published in the official gazette, these final texts settle some points raised earlier.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Full reviews of the final texts (and earlier) iterations are available elsewhere&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and many law firms have already issued newsletters providing overviews of the changes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I found it useful to mold a short 5-question FAQ of some questions that came up most often in the run-up to AIFMD II.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub-threshold AIFs: marketing and pre-marketing</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/sub-threshold-aifs--marketing-and-pre-ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/sub-threshold-aifs--marketing-and-pre-ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over summer, ESMA updated its Q&amp;amp;A on the AIFM Directive (EU Directive 2011/61/EU) with some new questions (and more importantly, answers) - including with respect to pre-marketing in a context of sub-threshold managers (AIFMs).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; ESMA confirmed that sub-threshold managers are not subject to the obligation to notify pre-marketing (unless otherwise required by national rules). The flip-side is of course that national rules will apply and should be considered carefully if a sub-threshold manager intends to (pre-)market in a EU jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new EC Retail Investment Package and its amendments to the AIFMD: focus on (un)due costs</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/the-new-ec-retail-investment-package-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/the-new-ec-retail-investment-package-and/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is nowhere near as sexy as the recently voted MiCA package, or as crucial for the future of our planet as the CSDDD, but the European Commission last week also came up with a ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_23_2868&#34;&gt;Retail Investment Package&lt;/a&gt;’ (the &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Package&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;) that is supposed to ‘empower retail investors’ and ‘make the EU an even safer place for people to invest their savings in the long term’ - which obviously are noble causes as well.[1]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New ESMA Q&amp;A on sub-threshold AIFMS doesn&#39;t really clarify much.</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/new-esma-qa-on-sub-threshold-aifms-does/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/new-esma-qa-on-sub-threshold-aifms-does/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the Alternative Investment Fund Managers Directive (AIFMD) the sub-threshold regime is largely left to national authorities. This regime applies to AIFMs that manage portfolios of AIFs whose assets under management fall below certain thresholds - essentially carving them out from AIFMD. Given the large stakes (i.e. falling under AIFMD or not), the relevant thresholds (and in particular their calculation) are highly scrutinized in practice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This makes it the more interesting that ESMA today updated its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esma.europa.eu/sites/default/files/library/esma34-32-352_qa_aifmd.pdf&#34;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A on the AIFMD&lt;/a&gt; with a question on the calculation of these thresholds, and in particular the interpretation of “substantive direct or indirect holding” in Article 3(2) of the AIFMD. However, the usefulness of ESMA&amp;rsquo;s answer in practice can be debated - the main take-away of the answer seems to be that there is no quantitative threshold, and solely a qualitative one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 noteworthy points on the EP ECON Committee AIFMD II final report.</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/noteworthy-points-aifmd-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/noteworthy-points-aifmd-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 24 January 2023, the EP’s Committee on Economic and Monetary Affairs (ECON) approved its amended draft (compromise) text of the amendments to the AIFMD and UCITSD (with 54 votes against 3, only the left-radical ‘The Left’ fraction voted against). The EP’s report (the &amp;ldquo;Final Report&amp;rdquo;) was published on 2 February 2023 and is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/doceo/document/A-9-2023-0020_EN.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Final Report follows a November 2021 proposal of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/transparency/documents-register/detail?ref=COM(2021)721&amp;amp;lang=en&#34;&gt;EC&lt;/a&gt;, an initial May 2022 draft report of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/doceo/document/ECON-PR-732549_EN.pdf&#34;&gt;EP ECON Committee&lt;/a&gt; (the “May Draft”) and a June 2022 ‘compromise text’ of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.consilium.europa.eu/doc/document/ST-9768-2022-REV-1/en/pdf&#34;&gt;Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final report on technical guidelines cross-border AIFM/UCITCs notifications</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/final-report-on-technical-guidelines-cross-border-aifm-notification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/final-report-on-technical-guidelines-cross-border-aifm-notification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right before Christmas, ESMA released its final report on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esma.europa.eu/sites/default/files/library/esma-34-45-1648_final_report_on_technical_standards_on_notification_letters.pdf&#34;&gt;draft technical standards on the notifications for cross-border marketing and cross-border management of AIFS and UCITS&lt;/a&gt;, after processing the responses it received on its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esma.europa.eu/sites/default/files/library/esma34-45-1471_cp_on_technical_standards_on_notification_letters.pdf&#34;&gt;consultation&lt;/a&gt; in this respect that closed on 9 September 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main changes made to the original standards are the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;a requirement to provide a LEI was introduced;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the information to be provided on delegation arrangements was toned down; and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the information to be provided on marketing strategy was toned down.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below, we will discuss this final report and the main changes over the draft report on which the ESMA consulted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
