<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marketing on Steven&#39;s Snippets</title>
    <link>https://SV1124.github.io/tags/marketing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marketing on Steven&#39;s Snippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2024 Steven Verschoot</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://SV1124.github.io/tags/marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sub-threshold AIFs: marketing and pre-marketing</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/sub-threshold-aifs--marketing-and-pre-ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/sub-threshold-aifs--marketing-and-pre-ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over summer, ESMA updated its Q&amp;amp;A on the AIFM Directive (EU Directive 2011/61/EU) with some new questions (and more importantly, answers) - including with respect to pre-marketing in a context of sub-threshold managers (AIFMs).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; ESMA confirmed that sub-threshold managers are not subject to the obligation to notify pre-marketing (unless otherwise required by national rules). The flip-side is of course that national rules will apply and should be considered carefully if a sub-threshold manager intends to (pre-)market in a EU jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New regulation on marketing virtual currencies to Belgian consumers</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/new-regulation-on-marketing-virtual-curr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/new-regulation-on-marketing-virtual-curr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crypto-winter does not only seem to be consolidation time for companies involved. It also is for legislators. With MiCA(R) on its way, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ejustice.just.fgov.be/cgi/article_body.pl?language=nl&amp;amp;caller=summary&amp;amp;pub_date=2023-03-17&amp;amp;numac=2023040640%0D%0A&#34;&gt;a new Belgian regulation on marketing virtual currencies to Belgian consumers was published in the Belgian Official Gazette this morning&lt;/a&gt;.[1]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The regulation is based on three elements:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;compliance with minimum rules to ensure that the information in the advertisement is correct and not misleading;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the mandatory inclusion of specific warnings in the advertisement; and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the obligation to notify the FSMA in advance of mass campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It also applies to influencers, and may even apply to so-called ‘shillers’ – so beware.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 noteworthy points on the EP ECON Committee AIFMD II final report.</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/noteworthy-points-aifmd-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/noteworthy-points-aifmd-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 24 January 2023, the EP’s Committee on Economic and Monetary Affairs (ECON) approved its amended draft (compromise) text of the amendments to the AIFMD and UCITSD (with 54 votes against 3, only the left-radical ‘The Left’ fraction voted against). The EP’s report (the &amp;ldquo;Final Report&amp;rdquo;) was published on 2 February 2023 and is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/doceo/document/A-9-2023-0020_EN.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Final Report follows a November 2021 proposal of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/transparency/documents-register/detail?ref=COM(2021)721&amp;amp;lang=en&#34;&gt;EC&lt;/a&gt;, an initial May 2022 draft report of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/doceo/document/ECON-PR-732549_EN.pdf&#34;&gt;EP ECON Committee&lt;/a&gt; (the “May Draft”) and a June 2022 ‘compromise text’ of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.consilium.europa.eu/doc/document/ST-9768-2022-REV-1/en/pdf&#34;&gt;Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
