<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UCITS on Steven Verschoot</title>
    <link>https://SV1124.github.io/tags/ucits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UCITS on Steven Verschoot</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2025 Steven Verschoot</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://SV1124.github.io/tags/ucits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New FSMA outsourcing guidelines for AIFMs, UCITS and asset managers/investment advisors - 10 key take-aways and 2 bis rounds</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/new-fsma-outsourcing-guidelines-for-aifm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/new-fsma-outsourcing-guidelines-for-aifm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AIFMs, UCITS managers and asset managers/investment advisors are allowed to delegate certain functions under the AIFMD and its implementing laws.*1 The Belgian regulator FSMA has recently issued &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fsma.be/en/news/outsourcing-handbook&#34;&gt;detailed guidelines on outsourcing&lt;/a&gt;, aimed specifically at AIFMs, UCITS and asset managers/investment advisors (hereafter referred to as ‘Companies’*2) - amidst a more general increased scrutiny vis-à-vis outsourcing arrangements by regulated entities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although not revolutionary, the guidelines provide significant extra body to applicable outsourcing requirements. They a.o. give further detail on the application of the proportionality principle to outsourcing and some general outsourcing principles (a.o. with regard to intra-group outsourcing). They also provide extensive guidance on the principles of sound management that must be taken into account when outsourcing. Consequently, existing outsourcing procedures and policies of (especially) licensed AIFMs, UCITs and asset managers/investment advisors might need a read-through.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub-threshold AIFs: marketing and pre-marketing</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/sub-threshold-aifs--marketing-and-pre-ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/sub-threshold-aifs--marketing-and-pre-ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over summer, ESMA updated its Q&amp;amp;A on the AIFM Directive (EU Directive 2011/61/EU) with some new questions (and more importantly, answers) - including with respect to pre-marketing in a context of sub-threshold managers (AIFMs).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; ESMA confirmed that sub-threshold managers are not subject to the obligation to notify pre-marketing (unless otherwise required by national rules). The flip-side is of course that national rules will apply and should be considered carefully if a sub-threshold manager intends to (pre-)market in a EU jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Final report on technical guidelines cross-border AIFM/UCITCs notifications</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/final-report-on-technical-guidelines-cross-border-aifm-notification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/final-report-on-technical-guidelines-cross-border-aifm-notification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right before Christmas, ESMA released its final report on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esma.europa.eu/sites/default/files/library/esma-34-45-1648_final_report_on_technical_standards_on_notification_letters.pdf&#34;&gt;draft technical standards on the notifications for cross-border marketing and cross-border management of AIFS and UCITS&lt;/a&gt;, after processing the responses it received on its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esma.europa.eu/sites/default/files/library/esma34-45-1471_cp_on_technical_standards_on_notification_letters.pdf&#34;&gt;consultation&lt;/a&gt; in this respect that closed on 9 September 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main changes made to the original standards are the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;a requirement to provide a LEI was introduced;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the information to be provided on delegation arrangements was toned down; and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the information to be provided on marketing strategy was toned down.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below, we will discuss this final report and the main changes over the draft report on which the ESMA consulted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
