<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Steven&#39;s Snippets</title>
    <link>https://SV1124.github.io/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Steven&#39;s Snippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2024 Steven Verschoot</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://SV1124.github.io/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>De hemel bestormen</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/de-hemel-bestormen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/de-hemel-bestormen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Het is al even stil op deze blog. De redenen daarvan zijn velerlei, maar voornamelijk te vinden in het gegeven dat ik me met zo veel zaken kan vermaken dat ik er niet aan toe kom om hier te schrijven.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dat is jammer, want op microbloggingplatformen kan ik wel actief zijn. Daar kruipt nochtans ook tijd in, men merkt het gewoon minder. In het licht van recente ontwikkelingen verlegde ik mijn focus van X (waar ik mijn account opzegde) naar Bluesky (waar ik een account activeerde). Ik post er over allerlei zaken, maar vermijd politiek - dat eindigt immers, net zoals op X het geval was, snel in oeverloze discussies en (erger) zeer snedige en venijnige opmerkingen die het plezier eruit halen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I switched to Firefox (and maybe you should too)</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/why-i-switched-to-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/why-i-switched-to-firefox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short while ago, I had a minor issue with my computer. I called our IT service provider, who quickly came to my assistance. He wanted to download something and went out looking for Chrome when he saw the Firefox logo on my taskbar. &amp;ldquo;Oh, you are still using that?&amp;rdquo;. As if I still had Netscape or Internet Explorer - or something.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His reaction is emblematic. Together with the sharp increase of the use of Chrome (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.computerworld.com/article/3261009/googles-chromium-browser-explained.html&#34;&gt;and other Chromium-based browsers with it&lt;/a&gt;), the use of Firefox has known a steady decline since its top around 2010 (see statcount chart &lt;a href=&#34;https://gs.statcounter.com/browser-market-share/desktop/worldwide#monthly-200901-202401&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Going live</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/going-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/going-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here we are, a brand new blog. Some old content, some new content planned. After a year of using LinkedIn for  blogging, I have decided I want to take it one step further and bundle some more stuff on here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This has various reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I get to keep better control over where my content ends up - if LinkedIn changes its business model, that&amp;rsquo;s not on me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do believe that a fragmented internet with easily accessible and searchable content is what the internet should be. I am very fond of the &amp;lsquo;minimal computing&amp;rsquo; idea&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. A personal website/blog better fits this bill than a linkedin blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How this website was built</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/how-this-website-was-built/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/how-this-website-was-built/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Websites usually do not have a &amp;lsquo;how it was built&amp;rsquo; page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But for this one, I felt compelled to have one. I would not have been able to build this without freely available tools, software and guidance. I am convinced that when taking stuff from a community, one should also use best efforts to contribute. Let this be my humble contribution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope it may provide some inspiration or help to other people considering building their own blog or webpage and looking past the well-trodden CMS, Wix&amp;rsquo;es or Squarespaces of this world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
