<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outsourcing on Steven&#39;s Snippets</title>
    <link>https://SV1124.github.io/tags/outsourcing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Outsourcing on Steven&#39;s Snippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2024 Steven Verschoot</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://SV1124.github.io/tags/outsourcing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A brief FAQ on AIFMD II</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/a-brief-faq-on-aifmd-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/a-brief-faq-on-aifmd-ii/</guid>
      <description>The final texts of AIFMD II were (finally) made available on the website of the council last autumn. Although not yet published in the official gazette, these final texts settle some points raised earlier.1 Full reviews of the final texts (and earlier) iterations are available elsewhere2 and many law firms have already issued newsletters providing overviews of the changes.&#xA;However, I found it useful to mould a short 5-question FAQ of some questions that came up most often in the run-up to AIFMD II.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New FSMA outsourcing guidelines for AIFMs, UCITS and asset managers/investment advisors - 10 key take-aways and 2 bis rounds</title>
      <link>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/new-fsma-outsourcing-guidelines-for-aifm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://SV1124.github.io/posts/new-fsma-outsourcing-guidelines-for-aifm/</guid>
      <description>AIFMs, UCITS managers and asset managers/investment advisors are allowed to delegate certain functions under the AIFMD and its implementing laws.*1 The Belgian regulator FSMA has recently issued detailed guidelines on outsourcing, aimed specifically at AIFMs, UCITS and asset managers/investment advisors (hereafter referred to as ‘Companies’*2) - amidst a more general increased scrutiny vis-à-vis outsourcing arrangements by regulated entities.&#xA;Although not revolutionary, the guidelines provide significant extra body to applicable outsourcing requirements.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
