<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mifid Investment Firms on Steven&#39;s Snippets</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/mifid-investment-firms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mifid Investment Firms on Steven&#39;s Snippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2024 Steven Verschoot</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/mifid-investment-firms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New publication on ETS emissions in EU financial regulation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-over-the-place-ets-emission-allowances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/all-over-the-place-ets-emission-allowances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I published an article in a peer reviewed journal: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.trv.be/trv/text.aspx?l=NL&amp;amp;id=1491&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;All over the place: ETS emission allowances in EU financial regulaton&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;,TRV-RPS 2024/1, 5-28.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the article, I provide a general overview of rules and obligations applicable to market participants that wish to hold or trade allowances - taking into account the recent updates of the Emissions Trading System.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This overview demonstrates that the common thread of allowances-specific rules is a plethora of information and reporting requirements. These apply to various parties, at various times, by different standards and to different recipients (and with overlap in subject matters).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ESMA MiCA consultations on reverse solicitation and qualification of instruments: interesting reads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-esma-consultation-on-reverse-solicit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-esma-consultation-on-reverse-solicit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new ESMA &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esma.europa.eu/press-news/esma-news/esma-consults-reverse-solicitation-and-classification-crypto-assets-financial&#34;&gt;consultations on reverse solicitation in the context of MiCA and the qualification of instruments as financial instruments vs. crypto assets&lt;/a&gt; are interesting reads, even if only because they basically give a read-up on the status of reverse enquiry and definition(s) of mifid financial instruments in general (in particular on the concept of &amp;rsquo;transferable securities&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As indicated by people wiser than I am on LinkedIn, the core can be found in paragraph 8 of the consultation on qualification of instruments, i.e.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ESMA review of national supervisory authorities&#39;​ positions on Brexit relocation of investment funds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/final-report-on-technical-guidelines-cross-border-aifm-ucits-notifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/final-report-on-technical-guidelines-cross-border-aifm-ucits-notifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an assessment of the Brexit relocation processes (available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esma.europa.eu/sites/default/files/library/esma42-111-7468_brexit_peer_review_report.pdf&#34;&gt;the website of ESMA&lt;/a&gt;), ESMA last December made some interesting observations on how different national authorities handle firms&amp;rsquo; relocation to the EU in the context of the UK’s withdrawal from the EU. The report focused on MiFID II investment firms, trading firm and fund managers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-findings&#34;&gt;General findings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The key findings of the report with respect to all three categories were the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
